<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Azure DevOps - Category - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/categories/azure-devops/</link>
        <description>Azure DevOps - Category - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/categories/azure-devops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>🚀 Azure DevOps Container Jobs: When Microsoft and Self-Hosted Agents meet, It&#39;s the Best of Both Worlds! 🌐🛠️</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/azure-devops-container-jobs-when-microsoft-and-self-hosted-agents-meet-its-the-best-of-both-worlds/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/azure-devops-container-jobs-when-microsoft-and-self-hosted-agents-meet-its-the-best-of-both-worlds/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Did you know that you can run your Azure DevOps jobs in a container? It&rsquo;s a great way to combine the benefits of Microsoft Hosted Agents and Self-Hosted Agents. In this post, I will explain what Azure DevOps Container Jobs are and how you can use them to your advantage. But first, a recap of Microsoft Hosted Agents and Self-Hosted Agents.
What are Microsoft Hosted Agents Microsoft Hosted Agents are a type of agent in Azure DevOps that are hosted and managed by Microsoft.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Your service connection credentials are mine</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/your-service-connection-credentials-are-mine/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 21:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/your-service-connection-credentials-are-mine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Like with the two previous posts Hacking Azure DevOps and I am in your pipeline reading all your secrets! I want to continue to raise awareness and understanding about pipeline security in Azure DevOps. In the previous post I have explained how secure / marked as secret variables are handled during pipeline runtime.
In this post I want to show how an Azure Resource Manager service connection configuration is handled during pipeline runtime.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>I am in your pipeline reading all your secrets!</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/i-am-in-your-pipeline-reading-all-your-secrets/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/i-am-in-your-pipeline-reading-all-your-secrets/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction With this blog post I want to raise awareness and understanding on how secure / marked as secret variables are handled during pipeline runtime in Azure DevOps and how these can be potentially exfiltrated. If proper security configuration is not in place this could potentially be abused by attackers.
Lets move ahead to create different types of variables and try to retrieve their values. By doing so at the end of this blog post it will be clear why it&rsquo;s not very sensible to give all project team members full access to pipelines.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Hacking Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2021/hacking-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 12:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2021/hacking-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction While this case is not a particularly new one and has been posted by Matt Cooper on devblogs.microsoft.com back in August 2020. I still feel that in relation to the possible data spillage it has not received sufficient exposure and the correct amount of awareness I would have expected. I actually stumbled upon this case by accident when playing with the Azure DevOps Library variables API.
So in this post I want to showcase how a possible attacker can use a compromised developers environment to gain access to almost all the data present in an Azure DevOps Organization.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>GitHub vs Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/github-vs-ado/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 13:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/github-vs-ado/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Recently one of our clients has asked if it might be worthwhile to look into GitHub. They are currently using Azure DevOps and are as far as I understand quite happy with it. So, I drew up a short summary of pro&rsquo;s and cons about GitHub vs Azure DevOps. The response that I got was very enthusiastic. And because of it I decided to share this information here.
Keep in mind that this is not a full in depth comparison of both products but more of a management summary intended to decide if it would be valuable to look into what GitHub can offer a company that is currently using Azure DevOps.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Set by step guide for a free and easy way to set up a low maintenance blog</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/free-blog-with-ado-and-github-pages/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/free-blog-with-ado-and-github-pages/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction I always struggled with the following; when I find a solution for a certain problem and months down the line I run into a similar problem and try to remember how I solved the previous one. Cursing at myself: Why didn&rsquo;t I write this down!? Like many other IT professionals I created a blog (years ago) to write those solutions down for myself and anyone who stumbles upon the blog.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
