<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/</link>
        <description>Jev Suchoi&#39;s personal blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>A quick and Easy Way to Add Renamable Display Names to Azure Resources</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/a-quick-and-easy-way-to-add-renamable-display-names-to-azure-resources/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/a-quick-and-easy-way-to-add-renamable-display-names-to-azure-resources/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this post I will share a couple of tips with regards to Secrets Management in your (local) dev environment. Personally I use these to prevent / limit leaking of secrets while developing Azure infrastructure. And I consider them as part of my security hygiene during the development process.
Last year I wrote a series of posts covering the naming convention topic. The perfect azure naming convention covered the Azure resources.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mastering Cloud Adoption Framework: Quick Start Backlog essentials</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/mastering-cloud-adoption-framework-quick-start-backlog-essentials/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/mastering-cloud-adoption-framework-quick-start-backlog-essentials/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework is a comprehensive set of guidelines, best practices, tools, and documentation. But, this comprehensiveness can render the framework complex and potentially overwhelming for individuals and organizations, most notably for those with limited cloud expertise. As an attempt to offset the complexity I created a ready to use quick start backlog for the Design Areas sub-section of the Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework . Via this blog post I want to share it, explain the composition and guide you on how import it into your own Azure DevOps organization within minutes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Don&#39;t spill the beans - keep your secrets secure</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 05:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the previous post Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management I shared the best tips for managing local secrets. In this post I will take Secrets Management to the next level by showing you how to create manage and use secrets securely by setting up a local secure store using PowerShell SecretManagement and PowerShell SecretStore modules.
Modules explained Since this approach to Secrets Management depends on the two just mentioned modules the purpose of each of the modules is explained next.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this post I will share a couple of tips with regards to Secrets Management in your (local) dev environment. Personally I use these to prevent / limit leaking of secrets while developing Azure infrastructure. And I consider them as part of my security hygiene during the development process.
Use Case When you are either building new Azure Infrastructure or debugging an existing configuration you will eventually need to use a secret or a password on you local (dev) environment.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to use Library for Azure Pipelines</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-use-library-for-azure-pipelines/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 21:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-use-library-for-azure-pipelines/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 6th post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps In this post the I will show how to use Library for Azure Pipelines.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Use Azure DevOps Demo Generator to create a new Project in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/use-azure-devops-demo-generator-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 21:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/use-azure-devops-demo-generator-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 5th post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps In this post the I will introduce you to the Azure DevOps Demo Generator tool by using it to create a new Project in Azure DevOps.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create a new Azure Service Connection in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-create-a-new-azure-service-connection-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-create-a-new-azure-service-connection-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 4th post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps . In this post the I will demonstrate how to create an Azure Service Connection in an Azure DevOps Project.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create a new Project in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 10:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 2nd post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps In this post the I will show how to create a new Project in Azure DevOps.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create an Organization in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-an-organization-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 21:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-an-organization-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post am kicking off a blog post series on working with Azure DevOps . The subjects covered by this series are organized into three categories:
Azure DevOps Fundamentals Azure DevOps Advanced Azure DevOps Expert Starting with the basic of basics of Azure DevOps Fundamentals :
How to create an Organization in Azure DevOps?
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The ideal Management group naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A new post and a new addition to the naming convention series . With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure Management groups .
Tip If you haven&rsquo;t already, don&rsquo;t forget to check out the other topics in the naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming What are Management groups and theirs limits If you are wondering about reasons for this approach to naming please have a look at the Naming convention background chapter of the The perfect azure naming convention .]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
