<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/</link>
        <description>Jev Suchoi&#39;s personal blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>🚀 Quickly Find Your Azure DevOps Project Id 🔍</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/quickly-find-your-azure-devops-project-id/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/quickly-find-your-azure-devops-project-id/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>With this post I want to share a lazy and a hacky way for finding the Azure DevOps <code>Project Id</code> of any project in your Azure DevOps Organization.</p>
<h2 id="the-lazy-api-query">The lazy API query</h2>
<p>It can feel a bit daunting to start using Azure DevOps API. But what most folks are not aware of is that data retrieval API&rsquo;s can be queried using
your favorite browser.
To get the <code>Project Id</code> we can do this with the projects <code>LIST</code> and <code>GET</code> API&rsquo;s.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🔍 Decoding Microsoft Azure: Understanding Platform, Landing Zones, Workloads, and Utilities ⚙️</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/decoding-microsoft-azure-understanding-platform-landing-zones-workloads-and-utilities/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/decoding-microsoft-azure-understanding-platform-landing-zones-workloads-and-utilities/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The task of explaining concepts of the Microsoft Azure Cloud befalls to us Cloud consultants. Usually we have to explain these concepts to stakeholders with varying levels of technical expertise. So using a simple analogy often helps to clarify complex ideas. In this post I want to share my favorite analogy. The house analogy! I am sure that I am not the first to come up with this analogy, however if you like my variation, feel free to use it in your own presentations or discussions.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🚀✨ I am in your pipeline, decorating it with compliance 🛠️🔒</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/i-am-in-your-pipeline-decorating-it-with-compliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/i-am-in-your-pipeline-decorating-it-with-compliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Back in 2022 I wrote a blog post <a href="https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/i-am-in-your-pipeline-reading-all-your-secrets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">I am in your pipeline reading all your secrets!</a>
 about how secrets can be leaked in <code>Azure Pipelines</code>.
I think it&rsquo;s time to offset that blog post and have a look at how compliance of all pipelines in a single <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/organizations/projects/create-project?view=azure-devops&amp;tabs=browser" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Azure DevOps Project</a>
 can be achieved. This is done by using a feature called <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/extend/develop/add-pipeline-decorator?view=azure-devops&amp;wt.mc_id=DT-MVP-5005327" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Pipeline Decorators</a>
.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-pipeline-decorators">What are pipeline decorators?</h2>
<p>In most organizations there are certain required compliance and security policies. For example; to be compliant with corporate policies a static code analysis tool must to be executed on all pipelines before executing the actual pipeline tasks. This is where pipeline decorators come in, pipeline authors don&rsquo;t need to remember to add that step. We as <code>Azure DevOps Organization</code> owners create a decorator that automatically injects the step into all pipelines during their runtime. Ensuring on an <code>Azure DevOps Organization</code> level that all pipelines are compliant with our organization&rsquo;s policies.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🚫 400 Bad Request. Access to Outlook on the web has been blocked by your organization 🛑✉️🔒</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/400-bad-request-access-to-outlook-on-the-web-has-been-blocked-by-your-organization/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/400-bad-request-access-to-outlook-on-the-web-has-been-blocked-by-your-organization/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>While this post is outside of my usual topics, I would like to share a solution for an error message which returns just a single search result on Google. I want to share it because it took me some time to figure out what was going on. So in case someone else runs into this issue this post might be helpful.</p>
<h2 id="the-issue">The Issue</h2>
<p>It all started after the network team updated the network to a new public IP. Right after this change all users started to get the error message <code>400 Bad Request. QWNjZXNzIHRvIE91dGxvb2sgb24gdGhlIHdlYiBoYXMgYmVlbiBibG9ja2VkIGJ5 IHlvdXIgb3JnYW5pemF0aW9uLiA8QlI+PEJSPkNsaWNrIDxhIGhyZWY9Ii9vd2Ev bG9nb2ZmLm93YSI+aGVyZTwvYT4gdG8gc2lnbiBvdXQu (Base64)</code> when trying to access Outlook on the web (OWA) in Microsoft 365.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🛠️ How to Build and Use Your Own Container with Azure DevOps Container Jobs 🚀📦</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/how-to-build-and-use-your-own-container-with-azure-devops-container-jobs/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/how-to-build-and-use-your-own-container-with-azure-devops-container-jobs/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In my previous post <a href="/posts/2024/azure-devops-container-jobs-when-microsoft-and-self-hosted-agents-meet-its-the-best-of-both-worlds" rel="">🚀 Azure DevOps Container Jobs: When Microsoft and Self-Hosted Agents meet, It&rsquo;s the Best of Both Worlds! 🌐🛠️</a>
 you where able experience Azure DevOps container jobs. In this post I am delivering on my promise and explain set-by-step how to build and use your own container with Azure DevOps Container Jobs. Buckle up, and let&rsquo;s get started!</p>
<h2 id="target-set-up">Target set-up</h2>
<p>Lets start by having a look at the target set-up.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🚀 Azure DevOps Container Jobs: When Microsoft and Self-Hosted Agents meet, It&#39;s the Best of Both Worlds! 🌐🛠️</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/azure-devops-container-jobs-when-microsoft-and-self-hosted-agents-meet-its-the-best-of-both-worlds/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/azure-devops-container-jobs-when-microsoft-and-self-hosted-agents-meet-its-the-best-of-both-worlds/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that you can run your Azure DevOps pipeline jobs in a container? It&rsquo;s a great way to combine the benefits of Microsoft Hosted Agents and Self-Hosted Agents. In this post, I will explain what Azure DevOps Container Jobs are and how you can use them to your advantage. But first, a recap of Microsoft Hosted Agents and Self-Hosted Agents.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-microsoft-hosted-agents">What are Microsoft Hosted Agents</h2>
<p>Microsoft Hosted Agents are a type of agent in Azure DevOps that are hosted and managed by Microsoft. These agents are pre-configured with certain software depending upon the type of agent (Windows, macOS, or Linux) which can run jobs targeting different platforms. With Microsoft Hosted Agents you trade off control for convenience as they are an excellent choice if you need to quickly scale your operations without worrying about the underlying infrastructure management.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>PowerShell Prowess: The 3 commands you need to know 👈</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/powershell-prowess-the-3-commands-you-need-to-know/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/powershell-prowess-the-3-commands-you-need-to-know/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Next to the Get-Command and hte Get-Help cmdlets, there are 3 other cmdlets that are essential for any PowerShell user. In this blog post I will explain my view on why they are essential and provide hands-on examples on how to use them.</p>
<h2 id="unveiling-object-properties-and-methods-with-get-member">Unveiling Object Properties and Methods with Get-Member</h2>
<p>The official documentation states: <em>The Get-Member cmdlet gets the members, the properties and methods, of objects.</em> Making it the Swiss army knife for exploring
the properties and methods of any object in PowerShell and thus indispensable for any PowerShell user.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Chaos to Order: Structuring IaC repository Like a Boss! 👑</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/chaos-to-order-structuring-iac-repository-like-a-boss/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/chaos-to-order-structuring-iac-repository-like-a-boss/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>With this post I want to share my new GitHub repository -&gt; <a href="https://github.com/thecloudexplorers/starter-kit-for-an-azure-iac-repository" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Starter Kit for an Azure IaC repository</a>
. This starter kit is based on best practices, personal experiences, and guidelines for creating and organizing code and resources tailored for Azure infrastructure deployment. While the example itself is based on a combination of Azure DevOps, Bicep and PowerShell, the concepts are applicable to any IaC language and tool combination.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A quick and Easy Way to Add Renamable Display Names to Azure Resources 💨</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/a-quick-and-easy-way-to-add-renamable-display-names-to-azure-resources/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/a-quick-and-easy-way-to-add-renamable-display-names-to-azure-resources/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In this post I will share a couple of tips with regards to <code>Secrets Management</code> in your (local) dev environment. Personally I use these to prevent / limit leaking of secrets while developing Azure infrastructure. And I consider them as part of my security hygiene during the development process.</p>
<p>Last year I wrote a <a href="/categories/naming-conventions/" rel="">series</a>
 of posts covering the <a href="/categories/naming-conventions/" rel="">naming convention</a>
 topic. <a href="/posts/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention" rel="">The perfect azure naming convention</a>
 covered the Azure resources. The primary concept for this naming convention is that in fact Azure resource names are actually ID&rsquo;s which cannot be renamed. In this post I want to share a method with which renamable display names can be added.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mastering Cloud Adoption Framework: Quick Start Backlog essentials 💪</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/mastering-cloud-adoption-framework-quick-start-backlog-essentials/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/mastering-cloud-adoption-framework-quick-start-backlog-essentials/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework</a>
 is a comprehensive set of guidelines, best practices, tools, and documentation. But, this comprehensiveness can render the framework complex and potentially overwhelming for individuals and organizations, most notably for those with limited cloud expertise.
As an attempt to offset the complexity I created a ready to use quick start backlog for the <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/ready/landing-zone/design-areas" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Design Areas</a>
 sub-section of the <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework</a>
. Via this blog post I want to share it, explain the composition and guide you on how import it into your own Azure DevOps organization within minutes.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
