<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Naming Conventions - Category - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/categories/naming-conventions/</link>
        <description>Naming Conventions - Category - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/categories/naming-conventions/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>The ideal Management group naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A new post and a new addition to the naming convention series . With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure Management groups .
Tip If you haven&rsquo;t already, don&rsquo;t forget to check out the other topics in the naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming What are Management groups and theirs limits If you are wondering about reasons for this approach to naming please have a look at the Naming convention background chapter of the The perfect azure naming convention .]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Git gud with branch naming</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to Git branch naming. This is the 4th and final post in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups When working in large teams, managing branches can quickly become a hassle. Comparing branches to figure out their feature set, is a time consuming and error prone activity.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A naming convention to bring order to variable groups</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure DevOps variable groups. This post is the 3rd in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention Git gud with branch naming The naming convention In my experience there are a lot of different way&rsquo;s Azure DevOps projects are organized. Also in contrary to the Azure resource naming variable groups are renamable and don&rsquo;t possess an ability to hold additional metadata like tagging.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The perfect Azure naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is the 2nd in the naming convention series . With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure resources. Why a naming convention is important is already covered by my previous post . However I do believe that some background is required to understand this approach. So, lets dig in.
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming Naming convention background A proper naming convention is one of the main methods for building and maintaining Cloud infrastructure as cattle and not as pets.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-10-commandments-for-azure-naming-conventions/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-10-commandments-for-azure-naming-conventions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are many Azure related naming conventions guides but this one is mine! For every 10 engineers and architects asked you will get 10 different replies on such a topic as naming conventions. With this blog post I would like to kick-off a small series of blog posts sharing my view points about Azure related naming conventions. In this post starting with why a proper naming convention is important and the 10 commandments I generally follow when working on a naming convention.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
