<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Cloud Governance - Tag - DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/tags/cloud-governance/</link>
        <description>Cloud Governance - Tag - DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/tags/cloud-governance/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>🌐💼 Building a Cloud Center of Excellence: The Pathfinder Journey 🌟🚀</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/building-a-cloud-center-of-excellence-the-pathfinder-journey/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/building-a-cloud-center-of-excellence-the-pathfinder-journey/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The concept of a Cloud Center of Excellence (CCoE) is well-documented, and many organizations recognize its added value in driving innovation and operational efficiency. However, while there is a wealth of information on what a CCoE is, practical guidance on how to effectively implement one is often lacking, leaving organizations with more questions than answers. Even comprehensive resources like <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/organize/cloud-center-of-excellence?wt.mc_id=DT-MVP-5005327" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Microsoft&rsquo;s Cloud Adoption Framework</a>
 primarily focus on the functions of a CCoE in its end-state without delving into the intricacies of its establishment.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>📊 Automating Azure DevOps Auditing: Configure Streams with PowerShell</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/automating-azure-devops-auditing-configure-streams-with-powershell/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/automating-azure-devops-auditing-configure-streams-with-powershell/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Managing compliance and governance in the cloud can be challenging, especially when it comes to an often overlooked yet critical system: your Azure DevOps organization. Ensuring proper auditing with securely stored logs in a centralized location is vital. Audit streams address this need by enabling you to send audit logs to a Log Analytics Workspace for detailed analysis and monitoring.</p>
<p>In this blog post, we’ll explore how to automate the configuration of Azure DevOps audit streams using PowerShell. We’ll focus on using a fully working script that not only automates the setup process but also ensures drift control. This guarantees that audit logs are consistently sent to your desired Log Analytics Workspace without the need for manual intervention. Let’s dive in!</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
