<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security Hygiene on DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/tags/security-hygiene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security Hygiene on DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 05:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/tags/security-hygiene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t spill the beans - keep your secrets secure 🤫</title>
      <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 05:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023//sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; I shared the best tips for managing local secrets. In this post I will take &lt;code&gt;Secrets Management&lt;/code&gt; to the next level by showing you how to create manage and use secrets securely by setting up a local secure store using &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/module/microsoft.powershell.secretmanagement/?view=ps-modules&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer&#34;&gt;PowerShell SecretManagement&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/module/microsoft.powershell.secretstore/?view=ps-modules&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer&#34;&gt;PowerShell SecretStore&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; modules.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;modules-explained&#34;&gt;Modules explained&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since this approach to &lt;code&gt;Secrets Management&lt;/code&gt; depends on the two just mentioned modules the purpose of each of the modules is explained next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management 💤</title>
      <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will share a couple of tips with regards to &lt;code&gt;Secrets Management&lt;/code&gt; in your (local) dev environment. Personally I use these to prevent / limit leaking of secrets while developing Azure infrastructure. And I consider them as part of my security hygiene during the development process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-case&#34;&gt;Use Case&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you are either building new Azure Infrastructure or debugging an existing configuration you will eventually need to use a secret or a password on you local (dev) environment. The most straightforward approach that is often used is to create a new variable and add the secret as a value to this variable. Effectively (temporarily) hardcoding the secret value into whatever you are working on. The following example sows such an approach, it should be quite familiar to everyone who worked with Azure and PowerShell in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
