<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Log Analytics on DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/tags/log-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Log Analytics on DevJev.nl | Azure, Cloud Security &amp; DevOps Insights for IT Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 02:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/tags/log-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>📊 Automating Azure DevOps Auditing: Configure Streams with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/automating-azure-devops-auditing-configure-streams-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2025/automating-azure-devops-auditing-configure-streams-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing compliance and governance in the cloud can be challenging, especially when it comes to an often overlooked yet critical system: your Azure DevOps organization. Ensuring proper auditing with securely stored logs in a centralized location is vital. Audit streams address this need by enabling you to send audit logs to a Log Analytics Workspace for detailed analysis and monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we’ll explore how to automate the configuration of Azure DevOps audit streams using PowerShell. We’ll focus on using a fully working script that not only automates the setup process but also ensures drift control. This guarantees that audit logs are consistently sent to your desired Log Analytics Workspace without the need for manual intervention. Let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🛡️ You Had Me at Bicep: Deploying Microsoft Sentinel Made Easy 💪</title>
      <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/you-had-me-at-bicep-deploying-microsoft-sentinel-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/you-had-me-at-bicep-deploying-microsoft-sentinel-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to quickly and easily deploy Microsoft Sentinel to an existing Log Analytics workspace using Bicep. This step-by-step guide simplifies the process, showing that deploying Microsoft Sentinel doesn’t have to be complicated—whether you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced cloud professional or new to Azure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-microsoft-sentinel&#34;&gt;What is Microsoft Sentinel?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Microsoft Sentinel, here&amp;rsquo;s a brief introduction. Feel free to skip this section if you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
