<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 07:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Getting along with winget - basic packed management</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-basic-commands/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 07:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-basic-commands/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[During my summer holiday I had a one day break from sunny weather so I decided to use the family tablet to fiddle with some PowerShell. As expected only the standard software was installed on the tablet. I could either start installing everything I need manually or use this opportunity dig a bit into winget . I hope you will enjoy both the basics and the advanced configuration experience shared via this post.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Git gud with branch naming</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to Git branch naming. This is the 4th and final post in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups When working in large teams, managing branches can quickly become a hassle. Comparing branches to figure out their feature set, is a time consuming and error prone activity.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A naming convention to bring order to variable groups</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure DevOps variable groups. This post is the 3rd in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention Git gud with branch naming The naming convention In my experience there are a lot of different way&rsquo;s Azure DevOps projects are organized. Also in contrary to the Azure resource naming variable groups are renamable and don&rsquo;t possess an ability to hold additional metadata like tagging.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The perfect Azure naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is the 2nd in the naming convention series . With this post I want to share approach to naming Azure resources. Why a naming convention is important is already covered by my previous post . However I do believe that some background is required to understand this approach. So, lets dig in.
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming Naming convention background A proper naming convention is one of the main methods for building and maintaining Cloud infrastructure as cattle and not as pets.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-10-commandments-for-azure-naming-conventions/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-10-commandments-for-azure-naming-conventions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are many Azure related naming conventions guides but this one is mine! For every 10 engineers and architects asked you will get 10 different replies on such a topic as naming conventions. With this blog post I would like to kick-off a small series of blog posts sharing my view points about Azure related naming conventions. In this post starting with why a proper naming convention is important and the 10 commandments I generally follow when working on a naming convention.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Change the SharePoint domain name in your Microsoft 365 Tenant</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/change-the-sharepoint-domain-name-in-your-microsoft-365-tenant/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:42:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/change-the-sharepoint-domain-name-in-your-microsoft-365-tenant/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Back when all the Cloud and SaaS offerings where a brand new concept most IT administrators ended up choosing the domain name of a tenant. This choice would be then reflected in the SharePoint Online url and the only way to change it was to create brand new tenant. Either due to the somewhat poor choice from the IT administrators, due to mergers, rebranding or acquisitions some organization ended up with lets say less desirable domain name for their SharePoint URL.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Your service connection credentials are mine</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/your-service-connection-credentials-are-mine/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 21:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/your-service-connection-credentials-are-mine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Like with the two previous posts Hacking Azure DevOps and I am in your pipeline reading all your secrets! I want to continue to raise awareness and understanding about pipeline security in Azure DevOps. In the previous post I have explained how secure / marked as secret variables are handled during pipeline runtime.
In this post I want to show how an Azure Resource Manager service connection configuration is handled during pipeline runtime.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>I am in your pipeline reading all your secrets!</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/i-am-in-your-pipeline-reading-all-your-secrets/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 08:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/i-am-in-your-pipeline-reading-all-your-secrets/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction With this blog post I want to raise awareness and understanding on how secure / marked as secret variables are handled during pipeline runtime in Azure DevOps and how these can be potentially exfiltrated. If proper security configuration is not in place this could potentially be abused by attackers.
Lets move ahead to create different types of variables and try to retrieve their values. By doing so at the end of this blog post it will be clear why it&rsquo;s not very sensible to give all project team members full access to pipelines.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Hacking Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2021/hacking-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 12:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2021/hacking-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction While this case is not a particularly new one and has been posted by Matt Cooper on devblogs.microsoft.com back in August 2020. I still feel that in relation to the possible data spillage it has not received sufficient exposure and the correct amount of awareness I would have expected. I actually stumbled upon this case by accident when playing with the Azure DevOps Library variables API.
So in this post I want to showcase how a possible attacker can use a compromised developers environment to gain access to almost all the data present in an Azure DevOps Organization.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>GitHub vs Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/github-vs-ado/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 13:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/github-vs-ado/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Recently one of our clients has asked if it might be worthwhile to look into GitHub. They are currently using Azure DevOps and are as far as I understand quite happy with it. So, I drew up a short summary of pro&rsquo;s and cons about GitHub vs Azure DevOps. The response that I got was very enthusiastic. And because of it I decided to share this information here.
Keep in mind that this is not a full in depth comparison of both products but more of a management summary intended to decide if it would be valuable to look into what GitHub can offer a company that is currently using Azure DevOps.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
