<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 21:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Use Azure DevOps Demo Generator to create a new Project in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/use-azure-devops-demo-generator-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 21:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/use-azure-devops-demo-generator-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 5th post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps In this post the I will introduce you to the Azure DevOps Demo Generator tool by using it ot to create a new Project in Azure DevOps.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create a new Azure Service Connection in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-create-a-new-azure-service-connection-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/how-to-create-a-new-azure-service-connection-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 4th post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps . In this post the I will demonstrate how to create an Azure Service Connection in an Azure DevOps Project.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create a new Project in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 10:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-a-new-project-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is the 2nd post in the category Azure DevOps Fundamentals of the blog post series on working with Azure DevOps In this post the I will show how to create a new Project in Azure DevOps.
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to create an Organization in Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-an-organization-in-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 21:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/how-to-create-an-organization-in-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post am kicking off a blog post series on working with Azure DevOps . The subjects covered by this series are organized into three categories:
Azure DevOps Fundamentals Azure DevOps Advanced Azure DevOps Expert Starting with the basic of basics of Azure DevOps Fundamentals :
How to create an Organization in Azure DevOps?
Since it much more fun to do research and play with technology in collaboration with others, Wesley Camargo will be covering some of the topics on he&rsquo;s blog , while other topics are covered by my here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The ideal Management group naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-ideal-management-group-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A new post and a new addition to the naming convention series . With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure Management groups .
Tip If you haven&rsquo;t already, don&rsquo;t forget to check out the other topics in the naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming What are Management groups and theirs limits If you are wondering about reasons for this approach to naming please have a look at the Naming convention background chapter of the The perfect azure naming convention .]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting along with winget - advanced package installation</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-advanced-installation/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 08:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-advanced-installation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In my previous post I went trough my experiences with using the basic Winget commands. And mentioned that anyone who needs more control over the installation options will quickly note that when Winget uses the default installation options when installing packages. In this post I would like to share with you how I managed to solve this and get the control I need during the installation process.
Winget Advanced installation, the override command The winget install documentation shows that an --override option is available, with an input &ldquo;A string that will be passed directly to the installer&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting along with winget - basic packed management</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-basic-commands/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 07:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/getting-along-with-winget-basic-commands/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[During my summer holiday I had a one day break from sunny weather so I decided to use the family tablet to fiddle with some PowerShell. As expected only the standard software was installed on the tablet. I could either start installing everything I need manually or use this opportunity dig a bit into winget . I hope you will enjoy both the basics and the advanced configuration experience shared via this post.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Git gud with branch naming</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/git-gud-with-branch-naming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to Git branch naming. This is the 4th and final post in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention A naming convention to bring order to variable groups When working in large teams, managing branches can quickly become a hassle. Comparing branches to figure out their feature set, is a time consuming and error prone activity.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A naming convention to bring order to variable groups</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/a-naming-convention-to-bring-order-to-variable-groups/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure DevOps variable groups. This post is the 3rd in the naming convention series .
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions The perfect azure naming convention Git gud with branch naming The naming convention In my experience there are a lot of different way&rsquo;s Azure DevOps projects are organized. Also in contrary to the Azure resource naming variable groups are renamable and don&rsquo;t possess an ability to hold additional metadata like tagging.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The perfect Azure naming convention</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 06:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2022/the-perfect-azure-naming-convention/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is the 2nd in the naming convention series . With this post I want to share my approach to naming Azure resources. Why a naming convention is important is already covered by my previous post . However I do believe that some background is required to understand this approach. So, lets dig in.
Tip Check out the full naming convention series :
The 10 commandments for Azure naming conventions A naming convention to bring order to variable groups Git gud with branch naming Naming convention background A proper naming convention is one of the main methods for building and maintaining Cloud infrastructure as cattle and not as pets.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
