<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>How To - Category - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/categories/how-to/</link>
        <description>How To - Category - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/categories/how-to/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>🔒 Keep Calm and Use Azure Bastion Developer SKU for Free 💻</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/keep-calm-and-use-azure-bastion-developer-sku-for-free/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/keep-calm-and-use-azure-bastion-developer-sku-for-free/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>In today&rsquo;s cloud-driven landscape, security is a shared responsibility for developers and engineers alike. Azure Bastion&rsquo;s Developer SKU offers a lightweight way to securely connect to virtual machines—and did I mention it&rsquo;s free? 🎉 In this post, we&rsquo;ll walk through setting up Azure Bastion Developer SKU using Bicep Infrastructure as Code, fostering a &ldquo;<strong>security is everyone&rsquo;s responsibility</strong>&rdquo; mindset as we go.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-azure-bastion">What is Azure Bastion?</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start with a quick recap for those who are unfamiliar with Azure Bastion.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🚀 Quickly Find Your Azure DevOps Project Id 🔍</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/quickly-find-your-azure-devops-project-id/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2024/quickly-find-your-azure-devops-project-id/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>With this post I want to share a lazy and a hacky way for finding the Azure DevOps <code>Project Id</code> of any project in your Azure DevOps Organization.</p>
<h2 id="the-lazy-api-query">The lazy API query</h2>
<p>It can feel a bit daunting to start using Azure DevOps API. But what most folks are not aware of is that data retrieval API&rsquo;s can be queried using
your favorite browser.
To get the <code>Project Id</code> we can do this with the projects <code>LIST</code> and <code>GET</code> API&rsquo;s.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Set by step guide for a free and easy way to set up a low maintenance blog</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/free-blog-with-ado-and-github-pages/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:42:15 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2020/free-blog-with-ado-and-github-pages/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I always struggled with the following; when I find a solution for a certain problem and months down the line I run into a similar problem and try to remember how I solved the previous one. Cursing at myself: Why didn&rsquo;t I write this down!? Like many other IT professionals I created a blog (years ago) to write those solutions down for myself and anyone who stumbles upon the blog. But unfortunately my blog at that time has followed the trend of the general population of IT related blogs. It withered away due to the lack of attention from yours truly.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
