<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>PowerShell - Tag - </title>
        <link>https://www.devjev.nl/tags/powershell/</link>
        <description>PowerShell - Tag - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devjev.nl/tags/powershell/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>PowerShell Prowess: The 3 commands you need to know 👈</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/powershell-prowess-the-3-commands-you-need-to-know/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/powershell-prowess-the-3-commands-you-need-to-know/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Next to the Get-Command and hte Get-Help cmdlets, there are 3 other cmdlets that are essential for any PowerShell user. In this blog post I will explain my view on why they are essential and provide hands-on examples on how to use them.
Unveiling Object Properties and Methods with Get-Member The official documentation states: The Get-Member cmdlet gets the members, the properties and methods, of objects. Making it the Swiss army knife for exploring the properties and methods of any object in PowerShell and thus indispensable for any PowerShell user.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Chaos to Order: Structuring IaC repository Like a Boss! 👑</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/chaos-to-order-structuring-iac-repository-like-a-boss/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/chaos-to-order-structuring-iac-repository-like-a-boss/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With this post I want to share my new GitHub repository -&gt; Starter Kit for an Azure IaC repository . This starter kit is based on best practices, personal experiences, and guidelines for creating and organizing code and resources tailored for Azure infrastructure deployment. While the example itself is based on a combination of Azure DevOps, Bicep and PowerShell, the concepts are applicable to any IaC language and tool combination.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Don&#39;t spill the beans - keep your secrets secure 🤫</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 05:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/dont-spill-the-beans-keep-your-secrets-secure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the previous post Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management I shared the best tips for managing local secrets. In this post I will take Secrets Management to the next level by showing you how to create manage and use secrets securely by setting up a local secure store using PowerShell SecretManagement and PowerShell SecretStore modules.
Modules explained Since this approach to Secrets Management depends on the two just mentioned modules the purpose of each of the modules is explained next.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sleep Worry-Free: The best tips for Local Secrets Management 💤</title>
    <link>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 02:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Jev</author>
    <guid>https://www.devjev.nl/posts/2023/sleep-worry-free-the-best-tips-for-local-secrets-management/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this post I will share a couple of tips with regards to Secrets Management in your (local) dev environment. Personally I use these to prevent / limit leaking of secrets while developing Azure infrastructure. And I consider them as part of my security hygiene during the development process.
Use Case When you are either building new Azure Infrastructure or debugging an existing configuration you will eventually need to use a secret or a password on you local (dev) environment.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
